{
    "__type__": "task_card",
    "loader": {
        "__type__": "load_hf",
        "path": "universalner/universal_ner",
        "name": "sr_set",
        "requirements_list": [
            "conllu"
        ]
    },
    "preprocess_steps": [
        {
            "__type__": "rename_fields",
            "field_to_field": {
                "ner_tags": "labels"
            }
        },
        {
            "__type__": "get_item_by_index",
            "field": "labels",
            "items_list": [
                "O",
                "B-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "B-ORG",
                "I-ORG",
                "B-LOC",
                "I-LOC"
            ],
            "process_every_value": true
        },
        {
            "__type__": "iob_extractor",
            "labels": [
                "Person",
                "Organization",
                "Location"
            ],
            "begin_labels": [
                "B-PER",
                "B-ORG",
                "B-LOC"
            ],
            "inside_labels": [
                "I-PER",
                "I-ORG",
                "I-LOC"
            ],
            "outside_label": "O"
        },
        {
            "__type__": "copy",
            "field_to_field": {
                "spans/*/start": "spans_starts",
                "spans/*/end": "spans_ends",
                "spans/*/label": "labels"
            },
            "get_default": [],
            "not_exist_ok": true
        },
        {
            "__type__": "set",
            "fields": {
                "classes": [
                    "Person",
                    "Organization",
                    "Location"
                ]
            }
        }
    ],
    "task": "tasks.span_labeling.extraction",
    "templates": "templates.span_labeling.extraction.all",
    "__tags__": {
        "arxiv": "2311.09122",
        "language": [
            "ceb",
            "da",
            "de",
            "en",
            "hr",
            "pt",
            "ru",
            "sk",
            "sr",
            "sv",
            "tl",
            "zh"
        ],
        "license": "cc-by-sa-4.0",
        "region": "us",
        "task_categories": "token-classification"
    },
    "__description__": "Universal Named Entity Recognition (UNER) aims to fill a gap in multilingual NLP: high quality NER datasets in many languages with a shared tagset. UNER is modeled after the Universal Dependencies project, in that it is intended to be a large community annotation effort with language-universal guidelines. Further, we use the same text corpora as Universal Dependencies… See the full description on the dataset page: https://huggingface.co/datasets/universalner/universal_ner"
}
